<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>third | Aniket Das</title>
    <link>https://aniket1998.github.io/tags/third/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://aniket1998.github.io/tags/third/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>third</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 10:41:09 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://aniket1998.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>third</title>
      <link>https://aniket1998.github.io/tags/third/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuous-Discrete Bayesian Filtering for Stochastic Differential Equations</title>
      <link>https://aniket1998.github.io/project/1sde/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 10:41:09 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aniket1998.github.io/project/1sde/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supervisor&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://users.aalto.fi/~ssarkka/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Prof. Simo Särkkä&lt;/a&gt;, Aalto University&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of the term project for Aalto University&amp;rsquo;s course on State Space Models, titled &lt;a href=&#34;https://mycourses.aalto.fi/course/view.php?id=20984%C2%A7ion=1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Non-linear Filtering and Parameter Estimation&lt;/a&gt;, I investigated the continuous-time Bayesian Filtering problem for continuous-time State Space Models governed by Stochastic Differential Equations. I studied the theory of continuous-time Markov Chains, Brownian Motion, Ito Calculus and and the Fokker Planck PDE. I also studied the Kushner-Stratonovich and Zakai Equations for likelihood calculations in SDE models. Finally, I studied and implemented exact and approximate Kalman Filters for Continuous-Discrete State Space Models, which are a special class of SDE based SSMs where the State Transition model is an SDE, and the observation model is discrete-time but may be non-uniform. The project report is available &lt;a href=&#34;https://aniket1998.github.io/files/sde_filter.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and the implementations are available in this &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Aniket1998/SDE-Filtering&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nonparametric Models for Image Generation and Interpolation</title>
      <link>https://aniket1998.github.io/project/1iccv/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 10:24:40 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aniket1998.github.io/project/1iccv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supervisor&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cse.iitk.ac.in/users/piyush/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Prof. Piyush Rai&lt;/a&gt;, IIT Kanpur&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We developed a generative model for images that uses Probabilistic Second Order Neural ODEs to learn a distribution of smooth continuous-time interpolation trajectories for a given source-target pair, and generates individual images by temporal subsampling of random interpolation curves that are drawn from the conditional (conditioned on the source-target pair) distribution of trajectories. The resultant model was formulated as a modified Generative Adversarial Network with a non-parametric data dependent latent code prior. We qualitatively and quantitatively demonstrated that our non-parametric approach significantly outperforms baseline GAN and Bidirectional GAN models that impose a fixed prior on the latent code, on both image generation and interpolation. Furthermore, our approach also allowed conditional generation and interpolation on out-of-sample data at test-time, with zero training overhead. This work is currently submitted to the International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV) 2021, and a preprint shall be made available soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
